Heat.
[Music]
Master, I've done it.
Endless interruptions by the ninja. But
at last, we have another source dragon
icon. We're one step closer to our
goals.
I know exactly what I must do next. And
no one, not even the ninja, will get in
our way.
>> Yes, master. The time of your glory will
soon be at hand.
[Music]
A mortal using the forge of the
forgotten is a grave insult. No one
still living is allowed to touch it.
>> And yet I have already done so.
>> There's only one solution. We must make
it so the one who used the forge is no
longer living.
>> You're welcome to try.
Lost in
together we will
fight
behind
what's right.
[Music]
As if we didn't have enough problems
already in the
>> sorry Lee got to run.
You're my best.
>> What happened to Lee?
>> Spectral draconians. You can't see them,
but trust me.
>> Get to cover.
[Music]
>> Did all the lees just decide to
sleepwalk at the same time? Is this
another one of his dance numbers?
>> No, this is something weird.
>> This is something weird. The same thing
happened when we were in Mysterium.
>> Sora, when did you get here? You bring
Raz, too. Long story, but no. I was
really looking forward to kicking him in
the gut.
>> What thing happened in Mysterium?
>> Those look like dragonians.
>> Yeah, but the kind that if they touch
you, they drain your souls or something.
What's with all the
>> Whatever you do, you cannot touch them.
>> Who would want to? That's what throwing
fire is for.
[Music]
>> I'm better at hitting things I can see.
>> Yeah, that's why I made this thing out
of a prismatic blade.
Is it safe to come out yet?
[Music]
>> We need to light this whole place up
with your lamp.
>> Great idea. Problem. How's that
possible?
>> I got an idea. Mia, get me to the top of
that house.
>> Get ready for a big boost.
>> Thanks.
[Music]
It's not safe out here. Go inside.
>> But what happened to Lee?
>> Okay, Sora, you got this. This better
work.
[Music]
Great. More of Lee.
What was that all about?
[Music]
It was less horrifying when we couldn't
see those things.
>> Now that I can see you, I can arrest
you. You think you can just drain souls
without a stamp certificate of soul
handling?
>> No.
[Applause]
[Music]
Huh? Why won't this thing work?
Lloyd. Aaron.
Um, Lloyd, I uh Aaron,
I I'm sorry.
>> Powers don't work on these things, which
is really just stupid. Luckily, ninja
are more than just our powers.
>> I was starting to think you left, cool
guy. Not yet. But now is a good time to
do exactly that. Come on.
>> What? We're saving people here.
>> The mission is over. We came for the
parents. Let's grab them and go.
>> For Ninja, saving people is always the
most important mission.
[Music]
>> Then you ninja are a bunch of clowns.
>> You mom is a bunch of clowns.
Zart, are the Forbidden Five the ones
doing all this? Maybe, but they're
really out of it. Like, they're asleep
playing those weird musical instruments
that the souls go into. What's really
going on here?
[Music]
My time has never been closer.
>> Lloyd, I think we're the only ones left.
These things aren't going to stop until
they get every one of us.
>> Don't tell me I finally found my parents
just to lose it all.
[Music]
>> Finally.
>> Huh?
>> What? Hop on.
[Music]
Maybe the ninja aren't as stupid as I
thought.
[Music]
The bounty. How did Where did autopilot
remote be installed for me? But it took
forever to get here.
[Music]
Oh, you saved us.
>> Let's not assume we're safe yet.
Wildfire's driving.
>> Wait, just how bad is she?
[Music]
Then we were trapped in Imperium, which
is from another realm, like I said. And
then things got really complicated. But
Sora, remember she thought her powers
were from Rayu, the little dragon. Well,
she
>> Aaron.
>> Yeah.
>> You haven't stopped talking since we got
on board.
>> I just have so much to tell you. You
don't have to tell us everything right
now, honey. We have time.
>> I think
I I think I need a hug.
Well, we don't have ninja skills, but we
do have hug skills.
[Music]
I tried not to lose hope you were still
out there somewhere. I'm sorry I didn't
find you sooner. Oh, we should have
found you. We got tricked by Lee's lies.
Like all those people in there.
>> So, everyone in the land of Lee are
someone's lost loved ones.
>> Pretty much. It was a very convincing
lie Lee pulled off. We should have seen
through it, though. What kind of amateur
detectives are we? Oh,
>> that's another story. I solved the
mystery at a tournament. I even have my
old notebook from when we used to play
detective games.
[Music]
I had the same feeling when we escaped
Mysterium.
>> You know what I'm feeling?
>> Sorry.
>> Not sorry.
>> If it's guilt about not being able to
help all those people that were
attacked. Yeah.
>> Huh? We're more alike than I realized.
>> We need to figure out where the five are
taking their souls and find a way to get
them back. I thought for sure
Thunderfang ate the Forbidden 5 or
something.
>> Maybe they were released when Aaron hit
Thunder Fang with that elixir that
released all his trapped souls.
>> Someone say my name?
>> We're trying to figure out how the
Forbidden Five are still alive. They
don't look too alive. It's like they're
hollow.
>> You think someone drained their life
forces?
>> Maybe. I don't know. My instincts
haven't been the best lately.
>> That's not true.
>> Lloyd, come on. Don't be so hard on
yourself, Aaron.
I'm the one who failed you. I should
have made finding your parents a higher
priority. But you did find them. I fell
for Roz's lies. Hey, kid.
I'm the one that really found your
parents.
>> Can't you just let them have this
moment?
>> Whatever. I just happen to know the
truth.
I see he hasn't unshhattered his
goodness or recovered his memories.
[Music]
There are some memories I wish I didn't
have. Going with Roz was a disaster. All
of you were right.
>> The journey was bumpy. Sure. But your
parents are alive and you have them
back. That's all that matters.
>> Yeah. I feel like I finally have a place
I belong again.
>> You also belong with the ninja.
>> Really? I don't have an elemental power.
The only way I could learn real
spinjitsu is when an evil tiger
tooththed jerk taught me.
You always told me I was special. But
I'm not special, Lloyd. I don't think
I'm a real ninja. Aaron,
don't say that. But it's true. I know
you're special. Maybe the most special
ninja there ever was. Eold said the same
thing. He made me promise to teach you
properly the teachings my master Woo
would have given you. The same master
Woo that caused the merge and all the
chaos that came with it.
When you told me my uncle caused the
merge,
I think I was in denial. I couldn't
accept it. I wish I could ask him why he
did it. But uh I've come to accept that
Woo passed on. Sacrificed himself in the
process of creating the merge. Actually,
no. He isn't dead. What? When I was with
Roz, I had to go to the Spectral Lands
to find that elixir. I met a departed
ninja who insisted Master Woo didn't
pass through there. Wu must be alive
somewhere, somehow. The spectral ants.
Yeah, they used to be the realm of the
departed in the cursed realm. Now all
mixed together. The spectral draonians
who attacked us look kind of like the
creatures who attacked the dead there.
>> Dead like Thunder Fang in the forbidden
5.
>> If they really died, they'd have had to
pass through there. I had another vision
and overheard the source dragons. They
claimed Thunderfang was still a threat.
Could he be in the Spectral Lands? I
suppose it's possible.
Change of course. We need to go to the
spectral lands.
Still terrible. How can you eat when we
just saw proof a source dragon was
killed? I didn't eat cuz it was gross.
[Music]
Oh no.
What is happening here?
I don't know. That fog rolled in out of
nowhere with that weird music.
>> Not
that guy's back. Aren't the Forbidden 5
dead?
>> Cole, you've got to see this.
[Music]
Gio, take the finders to the monastery
for safety. We got a villain to catch.
>> You're welcome.
>> We're not going in there, are we?
>> Well, you're not.
I'm programming the jet to take you back
to the monastery in Ninjago.
Huh?
>> Why do only they get to leave?
>> I'll find a way to get you more treasure
if you come with us. We're going to need
all the help we can get.
>> Especially ninja help.
>> Not a ninja, but not going to pass up
treasure.
>> Are you sure you should go in there,
Aaron?
>> The land of Le is filled with other
people's missing loved ones. I have to
do whatever I can to release their
souls. And I'm the only one who's been
in the spectral lands before.
>> When you're done here, we should go to
the Levat Springs like we used to every
summer.
>> Yeah, it's not there anymore. But we
definitely need a family vacation.
[Music]
Aaron
Should
[Music]
we have seen something by now? Anything?
>> Yeah. It's weird. The soul suckers don't
know we're here or that departed ninja
I'm
found something.
[Music]
None of this looks good.
That's the Well of the Lost. It's where
I got the elixir that saved Roz and
destroyed Thunder Fang.
>> What's down that well?
>> And where did those flying ghost things
that were with that guy go?
We got to get out of here.
>> It's like they're sleepwalking. Well,
sleeping or not, I'm sure they're
thirsty. Feted tea it is.
>> Visitors.
>> Is this the monastery?
>> Hello? Anyone home?
>> Um, who are you? Are are you supposed to
be here?
>> I think so. Sora put the jet on
autopilot. We're Aaron's parents.
What a pleasure.
I'm Mr. Fro Higgy, assistant keeper of
the monastery, and I'm thrilled to see
my belief in your demise was incorrect.
>> Uh, thanks. We don't want to intrude,
but we heard our old house is gone, and
something called the crossroads is there
now.
>> All true. All true. But we have a place
here you can stay.
Aaron's old room. Make yourself at home.
Unfortunately, I'm needed to help our
other guests.
>> Is that
>> our old porch swing? Aaron kept it.
What is that thing now?
>> It's trying to lead us that way.
>> Should we follow it?
>> I don't have any better ideas.
[Music]
in here.
Is this another
>> monastery?
Which means
a portal gate, a way back to the
monastery of Spinjitsu.
No, we need to go to the city of
temples.
>> Not exactly the time to visit your
boyfriend.
>> Not for Roi. Well, kind of for Roi, but
more cuz Thunderfang got beaten really
hard back in oldie times, right? At the
Battle of the City of Temples. It was in
Roiy's book.
>> Yeah. So, if there's a way to defeat
him, Roi will know. That is strangely
logical
to the city of temples.
[Music]
>> Was there an invasion here too?
>> None of those draconian things.
>> And no roi.
[Applause]
[Music]
Hey,